已經幹掉它了嗎？
Did that kill it?
沒有
No.
我們需要那個來殺死它
That's how we kill it.
維山帝之書
The Book of Vishanti!
不能讓它奪走你的能力 快去拿書
We can't let it take your power. Get to the book.
要怎麼過去？
How do we get across?
跳
Jump.
抓緊
Hold on!
不…
No, no, no!
它太強大了
It's too strong.
我制服不了它
I can't hold it.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
這是唯一的辦法
This is the only way.
你在做什麼？
What're you doing?
我不能讓那怪物奪走你的能力
I can't let that thing take your power.
你控制不了你的能力
You can't control it.
但我可以
But I can.
我們是朋友啊
But we're friends.
你為何要殺死我
You're killing me.
我知道
I know.
但在放眼整個多元宇宙的龐大世界裡
But in the grand calculus of the Multiverse...
你犧牲的價值超過你的…
your sacrifice is worth more than your...
借過
Excuse me. May I?
謝謝
Thanks.
斯特蘭奇博士
Doctor Strange.
韋斯特博士
Doctor West.
有一陣子沒見了
Haven't seen you in a while.
我有五年變成塵埃
Yeah, I was a little preoccupied being dust there for five years, so...
很多人也是
So were a lot of us.
我不在的時候…
While I was gone...
謝謝關心
thank you for asking...
我失去了兩隻貓
I lost both my cats...
和我弟弟
and my brother.
很遺憾
I'm very sorry.
謝謝
Thank you.
晚上睡不著時我常在想
I guess what keeps me up at night is wondering...
非得那樣慘烈不可嗎？
did it have to happen that way?
有沒有別的路可行？
Was there any other path?
沒有
No.
我用了僅有的方法
No, I made the only play we had.
那當然
Well, of course you did.
一流外科醫師又是最棒的超級英雄
The best surgeon and the best superhero.
但你還是沒擄獲佳人芳心
But you still didn't get the girl.
麻煩一杯紅酒
Glass of red, please.
我來效勞 小姐
Oh, allow me, miss.
太沒創意了？
Little too on the nose?
你 在我婚禮上？
What? For you, at my wedding?
不 我覺得很完美
Nah. I think it was perfect.
恭喜
Congratulations.
謝謝
Thank you.
查理來了
There's Charlie.
介紹你認識 因為他…
I have to introduce you because he's kind of...
有點丟臉 他是鐵粉
It's embarrassing, but he's a big fan, so...
克裡斯汀
Hey, Christine.
我應該…
I should've...
真希望當初不是那樣
I wish I'd have been different.
我始終關心著我們倆
I never stopped caring about us.
但我必須做出犧牲…
But I had to make sacrifices...
才能保護你
to protect you.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我們之間根本不可能
It was never gonna work out between us.
為什麼？
Why not?
因為 史蒂芬
Because, Stephen...
你非得掌控一切不可
you have to be the one holding the knife.
我一向尊重你 卻無法因此愛你
And I always respected you for it, but I couldn't love you for it.
這句話你忍了多久？
How long you had that one in the barrel?
很久了
Long time.
我想也是
Yeah. I bet.
聽著
Look...
我真的很高興你找到幸福
Truly, I'm just glad that you're happy.
我很幸福
I am.
真的很幸福
I really, really am.
那就好
Good.
你呢？
Are you?
我很幸福
I'm happy.
那就好
Good.
你值得幸福
You deserve it.
小心 那是什麼？
Oh, man. Look out! What is that?
老兄
Dude!
謝謝
Thank you.
哇
Wow!
不
No, no.
小心
Look out!
我認識你嗎？
Do I know you?
救命啊
Help!
別客氣
You're welcome.
知道向至尊魔法師鞠躬是古老習俗嗎
You know it's ancient custom to bow in the presence of the Sorcerer Supreme?
我知道那個習俗
Yeah, I'm aware of the customs.
撐住
Hold it, hold it!
不可思議
That's incredible.
是啊
Yeah.
天啊
Oh, God!
她是誰？
Who's this?
我正想問同樣的問題
Yeah, I was gonna ask the same question.
小鬼
Hey, kid.
那隻怪獸為什麼要追你？
What did that creature want with you?
你父母呢？
Where're your parents?
我們送她回…
We'll take her back to the...
她拿走我的懸戒
She took my Slingie.
她拿走你的懸戒
She took your Slingie.
太誇張了
Yeah, it was crazy, man.
天啊
Oh, my God!
我不會殺你 小鬼
I'm not gonna kill you, kid.
我拼了命想救你 記得嗎？
I just bust my ass trying to save your life, remember?
巨獸我能對付
Giant monsters I can clearly handle...
困擾我的是昨晚你出現在我夢裡
but what bothers me is that last night, you were in my dream.
那不是夢
That wasn't a dream.
那是另一個宇宙
It was another universe.
你們有多少多重宇宙的經驗？
How much experience do you guys have with the Multiverse?
我們有多重宇宙的經驗
We have experience of the Multiverse.
最近有件事與蜘蛛俠有關
Most recently, there was an incident with Spider-Man.
什麼人？
What man?
-蜘蛛俠 他有蜘蛛的超能力　-所以叫蜘蛛俠
-Spider-Man. He has the powers of a spider. -Hence the name.
好噁心
Gross.
他長得像蜘蛛嗎？
Does he look like a spider?
不 比較像人
No. No, more like a man.
爬牆 射蜘蛛網
Climbs walls, shoots webs.
-答對了　-從屁股射嗎？
-Yeah. Bingo. -Out of his butt?
不是　-不是
-No. -No.
也許吧 我也不知道
Well, maybe, I don't know.
我真心希望不是
Honestly, I hope not.
超詭異
Super weird.
這樣吃會肚子痛
You're gonna get a stomach ache.
我來自另一個宇宙
I'm from another universe.
你怎麼知道我的肚子跟你一樣？
How do you know my stomach works the same as yours?
不知道
I don't.
我根本不知道你是否來自另一個宇宙
I don't even know if you're from another universe...
所以我還坐在這裡等你啟發我們
which is why I'm still sitting here, waiting for you to enlighten us.
我不得不說
Gotta say,
目前我見過的兩個奇異博士
of the two Doctor Stranges I've met so far...
你不是我最喜歡的
you're not my favorite.
什麼意思？
Which means?
他不懂西班牙語嗎？
Does he not know Spanish?
我連他愛不愛說英語都不清楚
I'm not sure he even enjoys speaking English.
我離開一場美麗的婚禮
Look, I left a very nice wedding...
去救一個小屁孩 以免她被章魚吃掉
to save a smart-ass kid from getting eaten by an octopus.
-誰的婚禮？　-克裡斯汀
-Whose wedding? -Now tell me... Christine's.
-你去了？　-靠 你娶了克裡斯汀？
-You went? -Holy shit, you married Christine?
-能拍照嗎？　-不能
-Do you mind? -Yes, I do.
我沒有 對
No, I didn't. Yes.
你得跟我解釋怎麼回事
You need to explain to me what's going on.
那只章魚為什麼想吃你？
Why was that octopus trying to eat you?
那怪物想綁架我
That thing was trying to kidnap me.
它就像惡魔的爪牙
It's like a henchman who works for a demon.
我們只知道他們想奪走我的能力
All we knew is that they wanted to take my power for themselves.
什麼能力？
What power?
我能在多重宇宙間旅行
I can travel the Multiverse.
什麼？
What?
你能在不同宇宙間移動？
You can physically move from one universe to another?
怎麼做？
How?
問題就是我不知道
That's the problem. I don't know how.
我無法控制它
Can't control it.
只有在我非常害怕時才有辦法
Only happens when I'm really, really afraid.
我的分身能擊敗這個惡魔嗎？
Okay. And did Other Me know how to defeat this demon?
你們知道一本白魔法全書
Well, you guys knew of this magical book of pure good...
它給魔法師擊敗敵人所需的指引
that gives a sorcerer whatever they need to defeat their enemy.
維山帝之書？
The Book of Vishanti?
那不是真的
It's not real.
那是神話 不存在
It's a fairy tale. It doesn't exist.
其實它存在
Actually, it does.
成為至尊魔法師時拿到的秘笈中有寫
I found out in the secret book you get when you become Sorcerer Supreme.
不可思議
Unbelievable.
你不是至尊魔法師？
You're not the Sorcerer Supreme?
我不是至尊魔法師
No, I'm not the Sorcerer Supreme.
你的分身是他那個宇宙的至尊魔法師
Other You was Sorcerer Supreme of his universe.
是
Right. Yeah.
雖然它存在
Although it does exist...
維山帝之書據說無法取得
the Book of Vishanti is said to be unreachable.
沒錯 只是…
It is. Except...
我們取得了
we reached it.
結果那個惡魔追上我們
Then the demon caught up with us.
我以為你會保護我 可是…
I thought you'd protect me...
你沒有
but you didn't.
那是我夢中的那場打鬥
That was the fight in my dream.
那不是夢
That wasn't a dream.
證明給我看
Prove it.
那不是夢
It wasn't a dream.
這表示…
That means...
夢境是窺探多重宇宙自我的窗口
dreams are windows into the lives of our Multiversal selves.
那是他的理論
That was his theory.
所以我裸體被小丑追的惡夢…
So, that recurring nightmare where I'm running naked from a clown...
在某個地方是真的
Somewhere out there, it's real.
我在那個地方綁馬尾
Somewhere out there I had a ponytail.
可能會有更多怪獸來追殺她
There could be more creatures coming for her.
這能力在小鬼手中就夠危險了
The power is dangerous enough in the hands of a kid.
要是被真正的威脅取得呢？
Imagine if a real threat acquired it?
對了 年輕人 我們不知道你名字
It occurs to me, young one, we don't know your name.
阿美莉卡查維茲
America Chavez.
查小姐 願意跟我們到卡瑪泰姬嗎？
Miss Chavez, will you come with us to Kamar-Taj?
你在那裡會很安全
You'll be safe there.
我怎麼知道你不會跟他一樣背叛我？
How do I know you won't betray me like he did?
我想你只能相信我了
I guess you're just gonna have to trust me.
該拿他怎麼辦？
What do we do with him?
這樣違反規定
That's gotta violate an ordinance.
我埋過更糟的
Ah, I've buried worse.
殺死他的怪獸…
The creature that killed him...
有跟那只章魚一樣的記號嗎？
did it have the same markings as the octopus?
盧恩符文
Runes.
這不是魔法
This isn't sorcery.
是巫術
It's witchcraft.
有誰面對過這種東西嗎？
Do we know anyone who's faced such a thing?
我可能知道
I think I might.
巧克力
Chocolate!
我說什麼？
Hey! What did I say?
我們等不及了
But we couldn't wait.
我怎麼說的？
But what did I say?
去洗手
Go wash your hands.
媽 別這樣 我們年紀太大了
Mom, come on. We're too old for that.
好吧
Oh, okay.
你能幫我蓋被子 媽
You can tuck me in, Mom.
沒問題
I will.
你知道 家人是永遠的
You know, a family is forever.
就算想 我們也不可能真的離開彼此
We could never truly leave each other, even if we tried.
媽 我改變心意了
Mom, I changed my mind.
你要的話可以幫我蓋被子
You can come tuck me in if you want.
好
Okay.
愛你
Love you.
蘋果 對吧？
Apples, right?
最後會長出來
Eventually.
-聞起來…　-香甜
-Smells... -Sweet.
我想說真實
I was gonna say real.
千真萬確 謝謝
It's all very real, thanks.
我已經不碰魔法了
I've put the magic behind me.
看得出來
So I can see.
我知道你遲早會出現
Well, I knew sooner or later you'd show up...
想討論西景鎮發生的事
wanting to discuss what happened at Westview.
我犯了錯 有些人受到了傷害
I made mistakes, and people were hurt...
但你最後修正了一切 這點無庸置疑
But you put things right in the end, and that was never in doubt.
我不是來談西景鎮的
I'm not here to talk about Westview.
那你來做什麼？
Then what are you here for?
我們需要你幫忙
We need your help.
幫什麼忙？
With what?
你瞭解多重宇宙嗎？
What do you know about the Multiverse?
多重宇宙
The Multiverse.
幻視有他的一套理論
Vis had his theories.
他認為那是真的 而且很危險
He believed it was real, and dangerous.
這兩點他都說對了
Well, he was right about both.
我們發現一個能在其中移動的女孩
We found a girl who can somehow travel across it...
但有人在追殺她
but she's being pursued.
-誰？　-某種惡魔
-Pursued by who? -Some kind of demon.
覬覦她的能力
One that covets her power for itself.
我們帶她去卡瑪泰姬 雖然能自衛
We've taken her to Kamar-Taj, and we've got our defenses...
但我們用得上一個復仇者
but we could use an Avenger.
還有其他復仇者
There are other Avengers.
對 在留龐克頭的弓箭手
Yeah, but given the choice between the archer with the mohawk...
幾個與昆蟲同名的打擊犯罪高手
and several bug-themed crime fighters...
或是全球最強大的魔法師之間抉擇
or one of the most powerful magic-wielders on the planet...
答案顯而易見
it's an easy call.
到卡瑪泰姬來
Come to Kamar-Taj.
你又能被印在便當盒上了
It'll get you back on the lunch box.
要是你帶阿美莉卡過來呢？
What if you brought America here?
來這裡？
Here?
我瞭解孤單無助
Yeah. I know what it's like to be on your own...
因天生的能力而遭獵殺的滋味
hunted for abilities you never wanted...
我能保護她
and I can protect her.
-你還沒說她的名字吧？　-沒有
-You never told me her name, did you? -No.
我沒說
No, I didn't.
六邊域 Hex
<旺達在失去幻視後製造出來的範圍魔法，
可以將一定區域內的人、事、物按照旺達
的意願從分子層面進行改造>
六邊域不難應付
You know, the Hex was the easy part.
難的是說謊
The lying, not so much.
黑暗神書
The Darkhold.
<又名西索恩卷軸（Chthon Scrolls）
墮落成惡魔的上古邪神西索恩所著
此前置情節出自美劇「旺達幻視」>
你熟悉黑暗神書？
You're familiar with the Darkhold?
我知道它是死亡之書
I know it's the Book of the Damned...
接觸到它的一切都會墮入邪惡
and that it corrupts everything and everyone that it touches.
不知道它是否影響了你
I wonder what it's done to you.
黑暗神書只讓我看到真相
The Darkhold only showed me the truth.
我能再擁有曾經失去的一切
Everything I lost can be mine again.
你想對阿美莉卡怎麼樣？
What do you want with America?
你想如何利用多重宇宙？
What do you want with the Multiverse?
我會離開這個現實
I'm going to leave this reality...
到能跟孩子在一起的那個現實
and go to one where I can be with my children.
旺達 你的孩子不是真的
Wanda, your children aren't real.
你用魔法創造了他們
You created them using magic.
每個母親都是
That's what every mother does.
如果你知道…
If you knew...
有一個宇宙
there was a universe...
你在那裡很幸福
where you were happy...
難道你不想去嗎？
wouldn't you want to go there?
我現在很幸福
I am happy.
我最清楚什麼叫自欺欺人
I know better than most what self-deception looks like.
你公然違反所有自然定律
What you're doing is a flagrant violation of every natural law...
如果奪走那孩子的能力 她必死無疑
and if you take that child's power, she won't survive.
我並不樂意傷害人 史蒂芬
I don't relish hurting anyone, Stephen.
但她不是孩子
But she's not a child.
她是超自然個體
She's a supernatural being.
那麼強大的能力足以破壞各個世界
Such raw power could wreak havoc on this and other worlds.
她犧牲小我…
Her sacrifice...
能完成大我
would be for the greater good.
你別想被印在便當盒上了
Well, you can kiss the lunch box goodbye,
那是我們敵人用的借口
'cause that's the kind of justification our enemies use.
那是你的借口嗎…
Is it the one you used...
當你給薩諾斯（滅霸）時間寶石？
when you gave Thanos the Time Stone?
那是戰爭 我是不得已的
That was a war, and I did what I had to do.
你破壞規則 成為英雄
You break the rules and become a hero.
我卻變成敵人
I do it, and I become the enemy.
好像不太公平
That doesn't seem fair.
現在要怎樣？
What happens now?
回到卡瑪泰姬
Return to Kamar-Taj...
準備在日落前交出阿美莉卡查維茲
and prepare to hand over America Chavez by sundown.
和平移交
Peacefully.
然後…
After that...
你再也不會見到我
You'll never see me again.
不然呢？
And if we don't?
來找她的就不會是旺達
Then it won't be Wanda who comes for her.
而是緋紅女巫
It will be the Scarlet Witch.
緋紅女巫
The Scarlet Witch.
旺達不見了
Wanda's gone.
她取得黑暗神書 黑暗神書控制了她
She's got the Darkhold, and the Darkhold has her.
緋紅女巫擁有深不可測的魔法
The Scarlet Witch is a being of unfathomable magic.
她能隨意改寫現實
She can rewrite reality as she chooses...
不是將統治宇宙
and is prophesized to either rule...
就是摧毀宇宙
or annihilate the cosmos.
她用意志力控制了整座小鎮
She took over a whole town using her mind.
如果獲得阿美莉卡的能力
If she gets America's power...
她就能征服多重宇宙
she could enslave the entire Multiverse.
所以你求助的對象
So, the person you went to ask for help...
不但知道我在哪裡
and told exactly where I am...
也想殺我？
is the person that's trying to kill me?
對
Yeah.
立刻暫停教學 武裝學員
Suspend teaching at once and arm the students.
卡瑪泰姬必須轉為抗敵要塞
Kamar-Taj must now become a fortress.
哇
Wow.
是香港和倫敦至聖所的大師
It's the masters of the Hong Kong and London Sanctums.
能再一次跟您並肩拚死 是我的光榮
It's an honor to court death alongside you once again.
是我們共同的光榮
The honor is ours.
無論至尊法師如何要求，我們死而後已
Whatever the Sorcerer Supreme asks of us, it shall be done.
還沒有任務的人 跟我來
Extra duty men, follow me.
這是古老習俗
It's ancient custom.
小心說話
Choose your words wisely.
多重宇宙的命運可能因此改變
The fate of the Multiverse may depend on it.
瞭解
Got it.
不要有壓力
No pressure, then.
全是為了一個你昨天認識的孩子
All this for a child you met yesterday.
旺達 你有權利生氣
Wanda, you are justifiably angry.
你不得不做出莫大的犧牲
You had to make terrible sacrifices.
我在愛人的頭上炸出一個洞
I blew a hole through the head of the man I loved...
結果卻毫無意義
and it meant nothing.
不要跟我談犧牲 史蒂芬斯特蘭奇
Do not speak to me of sacrifice, Stephen Strange.
如果你給我我要的
If you give me what I want...
我就送你去能和克裡斯汀一起的世界
I'll send you to a world where you can be with Christine.
強大的卡瑪泰姬會聯合對抗你
The full might of Kamar-Taj stands against you.
就防守位置 準備
Defensive positions, now!
休想進入這些聖地
Do not dare to enter these sacred grounds.
你不知道我現在有多理智
You have no idea just how reasonable I have been.
對
Yeah.
死亡之書 自稱女巫
Book of the Damned, calling yourself a witch,
召喚怪獸綁架少女
conjuring creatures to abduct a kid...
我不覺得那叫理智
I don't exactly call that being reasonable.
派那些怪獸去追她而不是我自己，當然是仁慈
Sending those creatures after her instead of myself was mercy.
儘管你如此虛偽 又羞辱我
And in spite of your hypocrisies, and insults...
我一直求你不要從中作梗
I have begged you to safely get out of my way.
你磨光了我的耐性
You have exhausted my patience...
但我很希望你瞭解 即使是現在
but I do hope you understand that even now...
馬上就要發生的這些事
what's about to happen...
依然是我…
this is me...
非常理智的行為
being reasonable.
撐住
Hold!
搞定
Nailed it.
強化防護盾
Reinforce the shield.
Reinforce the shield!
強化防護盾
她想干擾他們的想法
She's trying to get in their heads.
魔法師 鞏固意志
Sorcerers, fortify your mind!
快跑
Run.
防護盾失效
The shield is down!
發射
Fire!
贊
Yes!
找掩護
Take cover!
任意發射
Fire at will!
撤退
Fall back.
王！
Wong!
快離開
Get out of here!
快走…
Go, go.
快走
Go!
阿美莉卡
America...
想要那個女孩 先過我這一關
You want the girl, you'll have to go through me.
好
Fine.
我們得馬上帶你離開
We gotta get you out of here. Now.
王 怎麼回事？
Wong, what happened?
卡瑪泰姬淪陷了
Kamar-Taj has fallen.
反射
Reflections.
她利用反射影像 蓋起來
She's using the reflections. Cover them.
你犧牲那些生命
You gave all those lives...
只為了不讓我接近我的孩子
just to keep me from my children.
是你殺了那些人
You took those lives.
不能讓你進入多重宇宙
You cannot be allowed to cross into the Multiverse.
我不是怪物 史蒂芬
I'm not a monster, Stephen.
我是母親
I'm a mother.
旺達 你沒有孩子
Wanda, you have no children.
他們不存在
They don't exist.
他們存在
Oh, but they do.
在其他每個宇宙裡
In every other universe.
我知道他們在
I know they do.
因為我會夢到他們
Because I dream of them...
每天晚上
every night.
我們表演出來
We're gonna show it.
媽 你看我們
Mom, watch us. Mom!
跑遠一點 回去…
Go long. Got it! All right, go on back, go on back.
好 不要…
All right, yeah. Don't...
夢到我的寶貝兒子
Of my boys.
比利 你敢！
Billy, don't you dare! No!
夢到我們一起生活
Of our life together.
-這裡　-贊
-Here. -Yes!
然後回到前面
And then back to front.
回到前面
Back to front.
我能吃嗎？
Can I have some?
拜託啦
Please?
-你們好了嗎？　-沒關係
-Are you guys ready? -It's okay.
我愛你 媽
I love you, Mom.
每天晚上
Every night...
相同的夢
the same dream.
每天早晨
And every morning...
相同的惡夢
the same nightmare.
要是你找到他們呢？
What if you reach them?
另一個你會如何？
What happens to the other you?
他們的母親會怎樣？
What happens to their mother?
你還好嗎？
You okay?
你救了我
You saved me.
希望如此
I hope so.
你竟然沒吐
Surprised you didn't puke.
這不是我第一趟怪異之旅
It's not my first weird trip, kid.
所以 這是紐約 在多重…
So, this is New York in the Multi...
對
Yep.
來了
There it is.
討厭
Crap.
別鬧了
Cut it out.
對 你傷痕纍纍
Yeah, you got pretty dinged up.
再幫你修補
We'll get you fixed.
好 阿美莉卡
All right, America.
你得打開一個入口 馬上回去
You gotta open a portal and get us back there right now.
我不會
I don't know how.
你剛剛做到了
You just did it.
不是故意的
Not on purpose.
王單獨對抗旺達 我是他唯一的希望
Wong is back there alone with Wanda, and I'm the only hope he has.
我不能控制…　-你一定可以
-I can't control my powers... -You must be able to control it somehow.
就連我都可以…
Even I could...
抱歉
Sorry.
這個宇宙的你呢？
Well, what about this universe's version of you?
或許她能控制她的能力
Maybe she could control her powers.
這個宇宙沒有我
This universe doesn't have a me.
-什麼？　-全都沒有
-What? -None of them do.
你怎麼知道？
But how do you know that?
因為我找過了
'Cause I've looked.
我也從來沒做過夢
And 'cause I never dream.
沒關係 小鬼
That's okay, kid.
就算你帶我回去 我也無力對抗旺達
And even if you could get me back there, I have no way of fighting Wanda.
維山帝之書呢？
What about The Book of Vishanti?
怎麼樣？
What about it?
你的分身認為它能阻止追我的東西
Other You thought it could stop whoever was after me.
我的分身真厲害 但他不在這裡
Yeah, well, good for Other Me. He's not here, is he?
我不知道它在哪 除非有另一個分身
I don't know where it is, so unless there's another Other Me...
我們得去找…
We need to go find...
我的另一個分身
Other Other Me.
紅燈通行？
We go on red?
記住多重宇宙旅行的第一個重點
Rule number one of Multiversal travel...
你什麼都不懂
you don't know anything.
對
Right.
紅燈了
It's red.
第二個重點是什麼？
So, what's rule number two?
阿美莉卡？
America?
阿美莉卡
America!
第二個重點
Rule number two...
找吃的
find food.
最好是披薩 披薩球
Preferably pizza. Pizza balls.
你拿什麼付錢？
How'd you pay for that?
免費的
It was free.
其實大多數宇宙的食物都免費
Food's free in most universes, actually.
你們竟然得付錢 好怪
It's weird you guys have to pay for it.
-喂 你沒付錢　-對
-Hey! You didn't pay for that. -Right.
完蛋
Crap.
或許這裡不能免費吃
Maybe it's not free here.
披薩老爸一定收錢
Pizza Poppa always gets paid.
披薩老爸 放輕鬆 她只是個孩子
All right, Pizza Poppa, relax. She's just a kid...
-她餓了　-你才放輕鬆 奇異博士
-She was hungry. -Relax yourself, there, Doctor Strange.
這披風哪來的？
Where'd you get this cape from, anyway?
感覺很像真的
That feels authentic.
這不是披風 是斗篷 建議你放開
It's not a cape, it's a cloak, and I suggest you let go.
這套服裝從奇異博物館拿的吧？
You took this whole suit from the Strange Museum, didn't you?
-奇異博物館？　-你個小偷
-Strange Museum? -You're a taker.
哼 你為什麼不吃點芥末？
Why don't you take some mustard, huh?
走吧 趁機快溜
Come on. It's not permanent.
他幾分鐘後就會停止？
Like he'll stop in a few minutes?
大約三星期
About three weeks.
我們經過的那些宇宙…
Those universes we went through...
我們是在改寫它們的歷史嗎？
were we paint in one of them?
對 最好別困在裡面
Yeah, you don't wanna get stuck in there.
每次都很難熬
It's really hard to eat.
你到過幾個宇宙？
How many universes have you been to?
72個
Seventy-two.
73 加上這個
Seventy-three, counting this one.
很多耶
That's a lot.
記憶信道 回放你的重要記憶
Memory Lane. Replay your significant memories...
（記憶信道）
優惠價實施中
...now at a discounted price.
我們記得 你才不會忘記
We remember so you don't forget.
好高級的餐廳
This is pretty fancy.
你得再申請一筆學貸嗎？
Did you have to take out another student loan?
不用 我剛賣掉了一顆上周手術中的腎臟
Nah. I just sold one of those kidneys that we operated on last week.
我要送你一樣小禮物
So got you a little something.
恭喜
Congratulations.
這什麼？
What is it?
打開來看看
Open it and see.
克裡斯汀 這…
Christine, this is...
太棒了 謝謝
This is amazing. Thank you.
我們沒空看這個
We don't have time for this.
記憶信道 回放你的重要記憶
Memory Lane. Replay your significant memories...
優惠價實施中
now at a discounted price.
我們記得 你才不會忘記
We remember so you don't forget.
這是哪裡？
Where's this?
我家
Home.
我的兩個媽媽
My moms.
阿美莉卡
America!
你說得對 這是浪費時間
You know, you were right. This is just a waste of time.
小鬼
Hey, kid.
那是你第一次打開入口吧？
That was the first time that you opened a portal, right?
不重要
Doesn't matter.
很重要 你失去了雙親
It does matter. You lost your parents.
我沒失去她們 而是殺了她們
I didn't lose them. I killed them.
不 你沒有 別這麼想
No. No, you did not. Don't even think that.
我用無法控制的能力打開一個入口
Okay, I opened a portal with the powers I can't control...
送她們去一個致命的宇宙
and sent them to a random, probably deadly universe...
-無法逃脫　-聽著
-with no way to escape. -Listen...
如果你媽媽跟女兒有一丁點像
if your moms are anything like their daughter...
她們就會活著
they survived.
相信你有一天會再見到她們
I'm sure you'll meet them again someday.
說得真好
Not bad.
謝謝
Thanks.
在你記憶銀行裡的女人
That woman in your memory bank thing...
是克裡斯汀吧？
that was Christine, right?
對 那是克裡斯汀
Yes, that was Christine.
-你怎麼認得她？　-你的分身
-How do you know her? -From Other You.
他們在一起嗎？
Were they together?
沒有 他們不聯絡了
No, they didn't talk anymore.
他搞砸了
He blew it.
當然
Of course.
你跟克裡斯汀的關係也搞砸了嗎？
Did you blow it with your Christine?
對 我想是
Yes, I guess I did.
為什麼？
Why?
說來複雜
Complicated.
比在多重宇宙被女巫追殺還複雜？
More complicated than being chased by a witch through the Multiverse?
對 是的
Yes, actually, it is.
（奇異博士奉獻生命 擊敗薩諾斯）
（向地球最強英雄致上永恆謝意）
「奉獻生命 擊敗薩諾斯」？
"Gave his life defeating Thanos"?
看吧？我們不全是壞蛋
Yeah. See? We're not all bad.
如果你的分身死了
If Other You's dead...
那誰是至尊法師？
who's Master of the Sanctum?
糟糕
Oh, shit.
-你認識他？　-對 莫多
-You know him? -Yeah. Mordo.
他是最早讓我進入卡瑪泰姬的人
He was actually the first guy who let me into Kamar-Taj.
太好了
Oh, great.
後來他性情大變 誓言追殺我
And then he snapped and dedicated his life to trying to kill me.
噢
Oh.
太好了
Great.
我始終認為這一天會來
I always suspected this day would come.
是嗎？
You did?
是
Yes.
因為你始終認為這一天會來
Because you always suspected this day would come.
我的兄弟
My brother.
好
All right.
進來
Come in...
跟我好好聊聊你的宇宙
and tell me everything about your universe.
紅燈通行
You go on red.
你也挺令人佩服的
And you're quite formidable too, it seems.
多重宇宙旅人
A Multiversal traveler.
感謝你帶奇異博士到安全的地方
Well, thank the stars you brought Doctor Strange to safety.
逃離不代表安全
Well, just 'cause we jumped ship doesn't mean we're safe.
我們的旺達有能力召喚惡魔與怪物
Our Wanda has the ability to conjure demons and monsters...
在其他宇宙攻擊阿美莉卡
to attack America in other universes.
她有黑暗神書？
So she has the Darkhold?
你知道黑暗神書？
Oh, you know of the Darkhold?
對 這個宇宙也有黑暗神書
Oh, yes. We have a Darkhold in this universe, too.
我在這個至聖所守護著它
I guard it here in this Sanctum.
我們絕不讓那危險武器落入敵人手中
We would never risk a weapon that dangerous falling into the wrong hands.
沒錯
Damn right.
如果你的黑暗神書跟我們的相似
But if your Darkhold is anything like ours, I'm afraid she can do far worse...
恐怕她能做的會比召喚怪物來追你更邪惡
than just summon monsters to come after you here.
什麼意思？
What do you mean?
書裡有一個咒語
There is a spell contained within those pages...
會侵蝕靈魂
corrosive to the soul...
褻瀆現實
a desecration of reality itself.
夢行
Dreamwalking.
夢行中的魔法師會將自己的意識
A Dreamwalking sorcerer projects their own consciousness...
從他們的宇宙投射至另一個
from their universe into another...
佔有另一個自我的身體
possessing the body of an alternate self.
他們可能操縱邪惡的分身
They may puppeteer this unholy doppelganger
從遠方追殺敵人
and pursue their enemies from afar.
這種佔有並非現實之間的永久連結
The possession is not a permanent link between realities.
他們在短短的夢行時間裡
But in the fleeting time they Dreamwalk...
能對入侵的宇宙造成無法挽回的傷害
they can do irreparable damage to the universe they invade.
所以你面對的或許不是惡魔
So it may not be a demon that you face.
可能是緋紅女巫
It may be the Scarlet Witch.
她為何不一開始就用這招？
Why didn't she do that to begin with?
當時她還能講理
Because that was her being reasonable.
你對維山帝之書瞭解多少？
What do you know of The Book of Vishanti?
黑暗神書的剋星？
The Darkhold's antithesis?
它能給魔法師制敵所需的力量
It can give a sorcerer whatever power they need to vanquish their enemy.
我需要你幫我找到它
I need your help to get me to it.
抱歉 史蒂芬
I'm sorry, Stephen.
但我特別希望你和其他人都瞭解
But I hope you, of all people, understand...
威脅我們現實的人不是旺達麥西莫夫
that it is not Wanda Maximoff who threatens our reality...
而是你們倆
it's the two of you.
-天啊　-茶裡加了什麼？
-Oh, God. -What was in that tea?
王八蛋
You son of a bitch.
尼山迪之沙(The Sands of Nisanti)
尼山迪之沙
The Sands of Nisanti.
我只是在做你會做的
I'm only acting as you would.
她來了
She's coming.
兒子 該上床睡覺了
Boys, it's time for bed.
我們能再吃一點冰淇淋嗎？
Can we have a little more ice cream?
-拜託啦　-拜託…
-Please. -Please, please, please!
-再一點點　-別逼媽媽當壞人
-A little more, please! -Hey, don't make Mom out to be the bad guy.
知道誰最棒嗎？
You know who's the best?
-誰？　-2003年的老虎隊
-Who? -2003 Tigers.
他們超遜的
They suck.
遜到爆
They're so bad they suck egg.
才怪 他們最棒了
No, they don't. They're the best.
-蠢蛋　-你才蠢
-Doofus. -Doofus 2.
你更蠢
Triple infinity doofus.
超級爆炸蠢
Infinity infinity googolplex quadruple doofus.
天下第一蠢到爆
Quintuple infinity... Crazy doofus.
宇宙無敵蠢
Googolplex doofus.
（生日）
媽
Mom?
什麼事 親愛的？
Yes, sweetheart?
你要去哪裡？
Where are you going?
丟垃圾
Just to take out the trash.
我們能給你看一樣東西嗎？
Can we show you something?
媽 快點
Mom, hurry, come on!
快來 很重要
Come on, it's important.
媽
Mom.
你一定喜歡
You'll like it.
來嘛 快點
Come on. Hurry up.
很重要
It's important.
媽 注意聽
Okay, so, Mom, listen to this...
我先開始
I'm gonna start it.
不 我先開始
No, I wanna start it.
-我想先開始　-不 我先開始
-I wanna start it. I want to start! -No, I want to start!
-我先開始　-我先開始
-No! I want to start. -I want to start.
你們一起開始吧
Why don't you both start it...
不管是什麼東西
whatever it is, together?
-好　-好
-Okay. -Okay.
-好了嗎？　-好了
-You ready? -Yeah.
三、二、一 開始
Three, two, one, go.
我們愛吃冰淇淋
We like ice cream
就跟每個小朋友一樣
Like every child should
如果吃了冰淇淋
And if we get some ice cream
我們保證會聽話
We promise to be good
你沒死
You're alive.
對
Yes.
可是很多人死了
But so many others were lost.
放了我
Set me free.
我必須摧毀那本書
I need to destroy the book.
不 不能由你動手
No. It cannot be you.
莎拉 不要…
Sara. No, no!
媽
Mom!
怎麼了？
What happened?
-什麼？　-你還好嗎？
-What? -Are you okay?
比利 湯米
Okay. Billy, Tommy.
什麼？
What?
不…
No, no, no.
我需要黑暗神書的咒語
I need the Darkhold's spells.
你是至尊魔法師
You are the Sorcerer Supreme.
把你知道的告訴我
Tell me what you know.
那你得殺了我 女巫
You're gonna have to kill me, witch.
不是殺你
Not you.
殺他們
Them.
旺達 住手
Wanda, stop.
旺達 求求你
Wanda, please!
那本黑暗神書是復本
The Darkhold was a copy!
復本？
A copy?
傳說有一座山
Legend speaks of a mountain...
你要找的黑魔法咒語刻在山壁上
with the wretched spells you seek carved into its walls.
黑暗神書抄寫在那裡
It's there the Darkhold was transcribed.
萬達格山
Mount Wundagore.
萬達格？
Wundagore?
沒人成功抵達過
No one has survived the journey.
也許我們會是例外
Perhaps we will be the exception.
喂！
Hey!
這個宇宙爛死了
This universe sucks.
斗篷呢？
Cloak?
喂
Hey.
喂 白袍哥
Hey, lab coat.
這是什麼地方？
Where the hell are we?
我不知道你是誰 你想幹什麼
Look, I don't know who you are, or what you think you're trying to do here...
-但這種情況…　-謝謝
-but these situations don't usually... -Thank you.
對沒本事的科學家通常不太友好
...work out well for the nameless scientists, so just...
克裡斯汀？
Christine?
你好 史蒂芬
Hello, Stephen.
查維茲小姐
Miss Chavez.
回答你的問題
To answer your question...
這是一個高度戒備的研究機構
you are in a highly secure research facility.
你們倆 加上你有知覺的斗篷
The two of you, along with your sentient cloak...
是來接受監視與檢驗的
are here for surveillance and testing.
檢驗？
Testing?
對 你們是來自另一個宇宙的訪客
Well, yes. You're visitors from another universe.
你們的磁場可能有輻射的
Your magnetic signatures could be radioactive...
你們可能有我們無法治療的疾病
you may be carrying diseases we just don't have treatments for.
因此才用這些漂亮的聚碳酸酯魚缸
Hence, these amazing polycarbonate fish bowls.
所以我該謝謝你囉？
I assume I have you to thank for these then?
是 我用尼山迪之沙研發出來的
Yes. I developed those using the Sands of Nisanti.
838史蒂芬的魔法遺跡之一
One of 838 Stephen's magical relics.
838史蒂芬？
838 Stephen?
那是我的機器人版還是…
Is that some kind of cyborg me, or...
我們宇宙是838
Our universe is 838,
你們宇宙的編號是616
and we've designated yours 616.
你們一定非常瞭解多重宇宙
You guys sure must know a lot about the Multiverse...
竟有人負責幫各個現實命名
if you got someone going around naming realities.
對
Yes.
就是我
Me.
我是巴克斯特基金會資深研究員
I'm a senior fellow with the Baxter Foundation...
專長是多重宇宙研究
and I specialize in Multiversal research.
你怎麼會來這裡工作？
So, how'd you end up working here?
不管這是哪裡
Wherever here is.
我自願加入
Well, I volunteered.
在你的葬禮上
At your funeral.
謝謝你去參加
Thank you for going.
你們的傷都很像 但不完全一樣
Your injuries, they're similar, but they're not identical.
很有意思
It's fascinating.
（98.6%相符）
我們在這個宇宙是什麼關係？
What were we to each other in this universe?
我們一直沒搞清楚
We never quite figured that out.
是嗎？
Yeah?
這算是我們的共同點
Well, that's something we got in common.
克裡斯汀 你得讓我們出去
Christine, you gotta let us out of here.
現在人人深陷危機
Everyone's in real danger.
我知道你不瞭解我
Look, I know you don't know me...
我也不想
And I don't want to.
在你的宇宙裡我是你的誰都不要緊
Whatever I was to you in your universe does not matter.
為什麼？
Why not?
因為你很危險 史蒂芬
Because you're dangerous, Stephen.
我的宇宙有人要抓那個女孩
Someone from my universe wants that girl...
對方會徹底摧毀這個地方
and she's gonna rip this place apart atom-by-atom...
不達目的絕不罷休
until she gets what she wants.
我不管你們來自復仇者聯盟或神盾局
So I don't care if you're from the Avengers or S.H.I.E.L.D...
都不是
We're neither.
那是什麼？
Well, what then?
九頭蛇？
HYDRA?
光照會現在要見你
The Illuminati will see you now.
光照什麼會？
The Illumi-what-y?
別讓人傷害那個小鬼
Don't let anyone hurt that kid.
不會有事的
It's gonna be okay.
你不能直接帶我們上去嗎？
You couldn't portal us up there?
我的魔法只能帶我們到這裡
My magic can only take us so far.
秘術師不該踏上…
Masters of the Mystic Arts weren't meant to tread...
萬達格山禁地
upon the forbidden grounds of Wundagore.
很久以前 第一個惡魔西索恩
Eons ago, the first demon, Chthon, carved his dark magic...
將他的黑暗魔法刻在這座陵墓上
into this tomb.
同樣的咒語後來抄入黑暗神書
These same spells were later transcribed into the Darkhold.
外人無法得知裡面有什麼無情怪物
There's no telling what soulless monstrosities lie within.
它們一直在等我
They've been waiting for me.
這不是陵墓
This isn't a tomb.
而是王座
It's a throne.
史蒂芬斯特蘭奇
Stephen Strange...
你被召喚到光照會面前
you are now called before the Illuminati.
我卡爾莫多男爵 至尊魔法師特此…
I, Baron Karl Mordo, the Sorcerer Supreme, do hereby...
卡爾？
"Karl"?
卡特隊長
Captain Carter.
第一位復仇者
The first Avenger.
布拉卡格博特貢
Blackagar Boltagon.
泰瑞根迷霧守護者 異人族國王
Keeper of the Terrigen Mists, the Inhuman king.
布拉卡格伏特加
Blackagar Boltagon?
我西迪威士忌
Hidigy hidithere.
驚奇隊長 宇宙捍衛者
Captain Marvel. Defender of the cosmos.
以及當前最聰明的人
And the smartest man alive...
神奇四俠的李德理查斯
Reed Richards of the Fantastic Four.
你好 史蒂芬
Hello, Stephen.
神奇四俠
"Fantastic Four."
你們的歌有上排行榜嗎？
Didn't you guys chart in the '60s?
抱歉 你覺得這是在搞笑嗎？
I'm sorry, is this a joke to you?
有人頭上有叉子
Well, there's a guy over there with a fork on his head...
對 有一點
so, yeah, a little bit.
你得感激黑蝠王沒在談話時插嘴
Be grateful Black Bolt doesn't engage you in conversation.
為什麼？他有口臭嗎？
Why? Does he have bad breath?
這個斯特蘭奇比我們的更囂張
This Strange is even more arrogant than ours.
不 只是更有活力
No, just more alive.
那是現在
For now.
史蒂芬 你來造成現實混亂與失穩
Stephen, your arrival here confuses and destabilizes reality.
你留下的衝擊越大
The larger the footprint you leave behind,
對撞事件的風險就越大
the greater the risk of an Incursion.
對撞事件？
Incursion?
對撞事件就是兩個宇宙的界線侵蝕
An Incursion occurs when the boundary between two universes erodes...
兩者相撞
and they collide...
徹底摧毀其中之一或同歸於盡
destroying one or both entirely.
你的分身創立了光照會
Your alternate self created the Illuminati...
要做其他人無法做的困難決定
to make difficult decisions that no one else could.
今天我們要決定如何處置你和那孩子
Today, we're here to determine what to do with you and the child.
在我們投票前
So, before we vote...
如果有認真的話想說 就趁現在
if you got anything serious to say, now's the time.
有
Yeah, I do.
如果你們擔心對撞事件
If it's Incursions you're worried about...
你們真以為我的威脅比緋紅女巫大？
do you seriously think I'm a bigger threat than the Scarlet Witch?
如果小女巫決定夢行 我們能對付她
Oh, we can handle your little witch if she decides to Dreamwalk.
你們沒辦法 除非給我維山帝之書
No. No, you cannot. Not unless you give me The Book of Vishanti.
多謝關心 史蒂芬
We appreciate your concern, Stephen,
但我們擔心的不是緋紅女巫
but it's not the Scarlet Witch that we fear.
根據經驗 多重宇宙最大的危險是…
From our experience, the greatest danger to the Multiverse, it turns out...
奇異博士
is Doctor Strange.
等等 你們的奇異博士？
Wait. Your Doctor Strange?
擊敗薩諾斯而死的地球最強英雄？
Earth's mightiest hero who died defeating Thanos?
我們應該告訴他真相
We should tell him the truth.
我們最後一位成員
Our final member...
查爾斯澤維爾教授
Professor Charles Xavier.
什麼真相？
What truth?
我們的斯特蘭奇不是那麼死的
That's not how our Strange died.
你在想現在會發生什麼
You're wondering what happens now.
不是
No.
我已經接受了
That I've already accepted.
我真正想知道的是
But I do wonder...
你能逼阿美莉卡送你去任何宇宙
when you could force America to send you to any universe you want...
為何還要把她的能力佔有己有？
why take her power for your own?
你明知那樣會害死她
You know it would kill her.
為了保護比利和湯米
For Billy and Tommy, to protect them.
要是他們生病呢？
What if they get sick?
在無限的多重宇宙 每種病都有解藥
In the infinite Multiverse, there's a cure for every illness.
每個問題都有解決辦法
A solution to every problem.
我不願再失去他們
I won't lose them again.
就算盡你所能 旺達 你也控制不了一切
Try as you might, Wanda, you cannot control everything.
我可以
But I can.
看看你四周
Look around you.
它就刻在石頭上
It's carved in stone.
我原本就該統治一切
I was meant to rule everything.
但那不是我要的
But that's not what I want.
我只要我的寶貝兒子
I just want my boys.
犧牲掉一個孩子的命？
At the cost of a child's life?
雖然你不能和摯愛歡聚，但在其他的世界裡卻有圓滿
Is there no peace in knowing that even though you can't be with the ones you love...
這無法讓你感到一絲安寧嗎
there are worlds where you are together?
還不夠嗎？
Is that not enough?
不夠
No.
我們的斯特蘭奇並未因擊敗薩諾斯而死
Our Strange did not die defeating Thanos.
當時我們正處於戰爭
We were at war.
其他人團結起來阻止薩諾斯
While the rest of us banded together to try to stop Thanos...
史蒂芬卻一如往常選擇單獨行動
Stephen, as always, chose to go it alone.
他求助於黑暗神書
He turned to the Darkhold...
開始夢行
began Dreamwalking...
希望答案就在多重宇宙裡
in hopes that our salvation might lie in the Multiverse.
結果你猜怎麼樣？
And guess what?
並沒有找到答案 但他仍一意孤行
It didn't. But he kept doing it anyway.
一天晚上你召集我們
One night, you called us all together...
坦承你一直在夢行
confessed that you had been Dreamwalking...
你說的是「情況已經失控」
and in your words, "Things had gotten out of hand."
你從未告訴我們詳細經過
You never told us the details of what had happened...
只告訴我們你不慎引了發對撞事件
only that you had inadvertently triggered an Incursion.
朋友 你造成另一個宇宙毀滅
You, our friend, had caused the annihilation of another universe.
那個現實中的每個人都死了
Everyone in that reality died.
每一個人
Everyone.
史蒂芬否認黑暗神書的邪惡
Stephen renounced the Darkhold's evil...
但幫助我們找到維山帝之書
and helped us find The Book of Vishanti...
我們共同把它當武器 擊敗薩諾斯
a weapon we did use together to defeat Thanos.
但還剩一個最終的威脅
But one final threat remained.
我會懷念你的 朋友
I shall miss you, my friend.
我準備好了
I'm ready.
對不起
I'm sorry.
你們告訴克裡斯汀了嗎？
Did you tell Christine?
有
Yes.
那尊雕像…
The statue...
那尊雕像呢？
What about the statue?
你們立了一尊雕像
You built a statue.
世界需要英雄
The world needs heroes.
我們做出困難的決定
We made the difficult choice
因為我們知道斯特蘭奇的能耐
because we knew what our Strange was capable of.
或許是每個奇異博士的能耐
What, perhaps, every Doctor Strange is capable of.
大樓遭人闖入
The building's been breached.
不會吧 真天才
No shit, genius.
顯示安全狀態
Status report on sentries.
停在…
Stop where you...
回來
Get back!
停在原地
Stop where you are...
她要去找那孩子
She's heading for the child.
看好他 我們回來再投票
Watch him. We'll vote on our return.
史蒂芬 要是你逃離這房間
Stephen, should you manage to escape this chamber...
一定要引導阿美莉卡查維茲
you must guide America Chavez.
你在說什麼東西？
What the hell are you saying?
救那個女孩 去找維山帝之書
Save the girl and get to The Book of Vishanti.
那本書在這裡？
What? You have the book here?
對 你建立了一個中繼點
Yes. You built a waypoint.
查爾斯 我們不能相信他
Charles, we cannot trust him.
我想可以
I believe we can.
有人一時迷途
Just because someone stumbles and loses their way...
不代表他們會永遠迷失
doesn't mean they're lost forever.
我們看看你是哪種奇異博士
We will see what kind of Doctor Strange you are.
謝謝
Thank you.
（安全漏洞 啟動封鎖程序）
外力入侵
Perimeter breakdown.
全體衛兵出動
All sentries engage.
所有人都出去
Everybody out.
-入侵者接近　-快點
-Intruder approaching. -Now!
是旺達
It's Wanda.
（D24室 封控程序 越級控制）
奧創命令你停止
Ultron commands you to halt.
奧創命令你…
Ultron commands...
（壓力密封解除）
快點…她來了
Hurry, hurry! She's coming!
糟了
Oh, no.
旺達 住手
Wanda, stop.
你掌控了一個無辜女人
You've possessed an innocent woman,
但還是能懸崖勒馬
but you can still do the right thing.
放了她
Let her go.
求求你
Please.
我自己有小孩 能體會你的痛苦
I have children of my own. I understand your pain.
他們的母親還活著嗎？
Is their mother still alive?
是
Yes.
很好
Good.
會有人留下來撫養他們
There will be someone left to raise them.
旺達 黑蝠王嘴巴張開就能摧毀你
Wanda, Black Bolt could destroy you with one whisper from his mouth.
什麼嘴巴？
What mouth?
帶我去找維山帝之書
Take me to The Book of Vishanti,
我們一起對抗她
so that we can fight her together.
你沒資格發號施令
You are in no position to give orders.
等他們回來 我這一票將終結程序
My vote will conclude these proceedings when they return.
你還沒受夠嗎？
Haven't you had enough?
我可以陪你玩一整天
Oh, I could do this all day.
滾出我的宇宙
Get the hell out of my universe!
他們不會回來了
They're not coming back.
你剛剛表明要殺死你朋友
And you just cast your vote now to kill your friends.
那以前也沒為你帶來困擾
Not that that ever bothered you before.
在我的宇宙 你恨我
You know, you hated me where I came from.
我敢說你在這裡也偷偷恨我 兄弟
And I bet secretly, my brother, you hated me here.
你一定嫉妒死了
You must've been so jealous.
知道嗎？
Do you know what?
聽到我如此墮落 你一定樂壞了
I bet you were thrilled when you heard I'd been corrupted.
你大概一開始就給了我黑暗神書
Hell, you probably gave me the Darkhold to begin with...
你完全不瞭解這個宇宙
You know nothing of this universe!
你殺死史蒂芬斯特蘭奇才能掌控至聖所
I know that killing Stephen Strange was your ticket to getting the Sanctum...
成為至尊魔法師
to becoming Sorcerer Supreme...
加入你那個小丑馬戲團 光照會
and to joining your little circus of clowns, the Illuminati.
我準備好…
I'm ready...
投下我這一票了
to cast my vote now.
我想我開始懂了
I think I'm beginning to understand...
你的莫多為何不太喜歡你
why your Mordo didn't like you very much!
你被封死了
You're sealed shut!
後退
Okay. Get back.
哇
Whoa.
夠了
Enough!
拜託救救我
Help me. Please.
旺達麥西莫夫 你的意志被分身挾持
Wanda Maximoff, your mind is being held hostage by your alternate self.
抓住我的手
Grab my hand.
或許 如果我把你從瓦礫中拉出來
Perhaps, if I can pull you from under the rubble...
咒語就會破除
the spell will break.
你們還好嗎？
Hey! You all right?
沒事吧？
You okay?
嗨
Hey.
-還好嗎？　-還好
-You all right? -Yeah.
嗨
Hey.
她修補好它了
She fixed him.
-謝謝　-別客氣
-Thank you. -Yeah.
澤維爾說我建了維山帝之書的中繼點
Xavier said I built a waypoint to The Book of Vishanti.
你能帶我們去嗎？
Can you take us there?
我怎麼能相信你？
How am I supposed to trust you?
我知道發生了什麼 很遺憾他那麼做
I know what happened, and I'm sorry for what he did...
相信我 維山帝之書是唯一的辦法
but believe me, The Book of Vishanti is the only way.
對 你的辦法
Yeah. Your way.
你口氣很像我的史蒂芬
You sound a lot like my Stephen right now.
他非掌控大局不可 結果害死一萬億人
He had to be the one holding the knife, and then that knife killed a trillion people.
這個史蒂芬不一樣
This Stephen is different.
真的
He is.
其他的史蒂芬都不重要
It doesn't matter about all the other Stephens.
你跟他們不同
You're not like them.
聰明的小鬼
Smart kid.
手伸出來
Give me your hand.
別讓我後悔
Do not make me regret this.
不會的
I won't.
-可以走了嗎？　-跟我來
-Okay, can we go now? -Yeah, follow me.
這條隧道通往哪裡？
Where's that tunnel go?
河底
Under the river.
快走…
Go, go, go!
（警告 防爆門）
她去哪裡了？
Where did she go?
我警告過你
I warned you.
旺達分身 如果你在裡面
Other Wanda, if you're in there...
憋住氣
hold your breath.
-她死了嗎？　-沒有 爭取時間而已
-Did you kill her? -No, just bought us some time.
維山帝之書在裡面
The Book's through here.
只有史蒂芬打開過
But only Stephen's ever opened it.
可惡
Shit.
專屬我的魔法 只有我知道
An enchantment that's specific to me, something only I would know.
-等等 史蒂芬　-快想
-Wait. Stephen. -Come on.
快點
Come on.
史蒂芬
Stephen.
對
Yeah.
謝謝
Thank you.
不客氣
Sure.
芝麻開門
Open sesame.
下來 小鬼
Come on, kid.
你可以
You got this.
我們可以
We got this.
對
Yeah.
沒事吧？
You all right?
沒事
Yeah.
這是裂隙接點 宇宙之間的空間
This is the Gap Junction, the space between universes.
好 維山帝之書
All right, Book.
給我我需要的
Give me what I need.
-不　-不
-No! -No!
我的兒子
My boys.
這不是你孩子要的
This isn't what your children would want.
他們永遠不會知道
They'll never know.
或許不會
Maybe not.
但你會
But you will.
不會吧
Oh, no.
慘了
Oh, crap.
這個現實好像自己瓦解
It's like this reality collapsed in on itself.
對
Yeah.
或兩個現實相撞
Or two realities collided.
快走
Come on.
阿美莉卡時間不多了
America doesn't have long.
那我們要去哪？
So where are we going?
如果這宇宙還有一個至聖所
Well, if there's still a sanctum in this universe...
那可能有另一個我的分身的分身
then there might be another Other Other Me...
那是我們救她回來的最佳機會
and that's our best shot of getting back to her.
我明白你們為何這麼擔心對撞事件
Well, I can see why you guys were so worried about Incursions.
不管發生過什麼事
Whatever happened...
這個宇宙的你並未盡力阻止它
this universe's you didn't do a very good job of stopping it.
我會告訴他你這麼說
I'll tell him you said that.
有人嗎？
Hello?
站住別動
Stop where you are.
你怎麼來的？
How did you get here?
歪打正著
By accident.
你是誰？
Who are you?
你是什麼？
What are you?
我是我們之一
I'm just one of us.
來自多重宇宙？
From the Multiverse?
沒錯
That's right.
提出證明
Prove it.
我們有個妹妹
We had a sister.
唐娜
Donna.
可是她…
But she...
小時候就死了
She died when we were kids.
怎麼死的？
How?
我們在結冰的湖上玩耍
We were playing on a frozen lake and...
她掉進湖裡
she fell through the ice.
我沒辦法救她
I couldn't save her.
聽起來沒錯
Sounds about right.
但我們不談那件事 對吧？
But we don't talk about that, do we?
對 不談
No, we don't.
我想你的現實並非一直如此
Suppose your reality wasn't always like this.
我猜本來跟你的一樣 直到…
I suspect it was somewhat like yours until...
直到？
Until?
直到我迷失
Until I lost.
因為誰？
To whom?
你想怎麼樣？
What do you want?
我想回家
I just want to get home.
相信我
Yeah? Believe me...
長久以來我一直想離開這裡
I've been trying to leave this place for a long time.
黑暗神書
Darkhold.
你在這個宇宙裡守護黑暗神書？
You guard the Darkhold in this universe?
對
Yeah.
有充分的理由
For good reason.
這是個開始
That's a start.
我能利用它 幫我跟我的宇宙溝通
I could use it. It could help me to communicate with my universe.
小心
Careful.
黑暗神書會造成嚴重傷亡
The Darkhold exacts a heavy toll.
不是我冷血
I don't mean to be callous...
還能有多嚴重的傷亡呢？
but how much of a heavier toll is there left to exact?
不只是對它的現實
Not just on its reality.
還有對它的讀者
On its reader.
很遺憾你救不了你的宇宙
Look, I'm sorry you couldn't save your universe...
或許你能幫忙救我的
but maybe you could help to save mine.
你幸福嗎 史蒂芬？
Are you happy, Stephen?
什麼？
What?
你幸福嗎 史蒂芬？
Are you happy, Stephen?
這個問題是…
It's the question that...
克裡斯汀帕爾默
Christine Palmer...
在她婚禮上問我的
asked me at her wedding.
我說我當然很幸福
I said, "Yes, of course I'm happy.
我是力量強大的魔法師
"I'm a sorcerer with the power of gods.
怎麼會不幸福？
What man wouldn't be happy?"
然後我回到這間該死的鬼屋
And then I came back to this goddamn haunted house...
坐下來
sat down...
想著我為何說謊
and wondered why I'd lied.
我根本無意讓這一切發生
I never meant for any of this to happen.
我在尋找一個不同的世界
I was looking for a world where things were different.
在那裡我有克裡斯汀 我很幸福
Where I had Christine, where I was happy.
但我沒找到
But I didn't find it.
只發現更多的我們
All I found were more of us.
於是我幫那些史蒂芬一個忙
So I did those Stephens a favor.
你是否做過那個墜落的夢
You ever had that dream where you're falling...
彷彿你被推下高樓？
as if you've been pushed off a tall building?
那應該是我
That was probably me.
黑暗神書會造成嚴重傷亡
The Darkhold exacts a heavy toll.
好
Okay.
這樣更有理由別用它 交給我
All the more reason to give it a rest and let me have it.
不如這樣吧
Here's the deal.
我讓你用黑暗神書 你給我克裡斯汀
I'll let you use the Darkhold if you give me your Christine.
唉
Yeah.
我想她不會同意
I don't think she's gonna go for that.
是嗎？
No?
我也覺得不會
Didn't think so.
等著 我們來了
Hang on, we're coming.
你要怎麼用黑暗神書？
What are you doing with the Darkhold?
你要夢行嗎？
Are you going to Dreamwalk?
比夢行再多一點
It's a little bit more than just Dreamwalking.
你們斯特蘭奇都一樣
All you Stranges, you're the same.
我知道
I know.
你說得對
You're right.
我們都一樣
We are all the same.
但現在那孩子需要我
But right now, that kid needs me.
沒有你幫忙我絕對做不到
And I can't do any of this without your help.
我在夢行時 請你保護我的身體
While I'm under, I need you to protect my body...
以免他們因為我擅闖而攻擊我
in case they attack me for trespassing.
他們是誰？
Who's "they"?
地獄亡者的靈魂
The souls of the damned.
好
Okay.
不是有一個你必須住在那個宇宙
But doesn't a version of you need to live in that universe...
你才能夢行進去嗎？
so that you can Dreamwalk into them?
誰說他們必須是活的？
Who said they had to be living?
史蒂芬斯特蘭奇
Stephen Strange...
佔有亡者遺體是禁忌
possessing a dead body is forbidden.
禁忌
Forbidden.
擅闖者
Trespasser!
停止夢行 否則就面對永恆的後果
Cease your Dreamwalk, or face the eternal consequences.
史蒂芬
Stephen!
他們要把我拉下去
They're pulling me down.
史蒂芬
Stephen!
撐下去…
Hang on, hang on, hang on.
你在哪裡？
Where are you?
波歌利亞火盆
The Brazier of Bom'Galiath.
波歌利亞火盆-The Brazier of Bom'Galiath
<放大各種反應程度的法器，
包括物理反應、化學反應、魔法反應>
滾回地獄去吧
Go back to hell.
史蒂芬
Stephen.
我在這裡
I've got you.
你是秘術大師
You're a Master of the Mystic Arts.
他們是幽魂
They're spirits.
利用他們
Use them.
不！
No!
來啊
Come on!
斯特蘭奇
Strange!
竟然夢行 你這個偽君子
Dreamwalking. You hypocrite!
這次想要殺了我
This time, it's gonna take more than killing me...
不能只殺了這個
to kill me.
殺人兇手…
Murderer! Murderer!
我什麼都不想知道
I don't even wanna know.
不！
No!
-不　-不
-No! -No!
她掙脫了
She's breaking free!
困住她
Hold her!
斯特蘭奇 利用阿美莉卡的力量
Strange, take America's power!
沒別的辦法了
There's no other way.
對
Yeah.
這是唯一的辦法
This is the only way.
是我 在我分身的身體裡
It's me in Other Me's body.
你是來奪走我的能力吧？
You're here to take my power, aren't you?
搶在旺達之前
Before Wanda can.
沒關係
It's okay.
我現在懂了
I understand now.
不 阿美莉卡
No, America.
我是來告訴你要相信自己
I've come here to tell you to trust yourself.
相信你的能力
Trust your power.
我們就要這樣阻止她
That's how we stop her.
我無法控制它
I can't control it. I...
可以 你可以
Yes, you can.
你始終都可以
You have been all along.
每次你打開入口
Every time you opened a portal,
就送我們到該去的地點
you sent us exactly where we needed to go.
那第一次怎麼說？
What about the first time?
那也帶領你到現在這一刻
Even that led you to this moment...
你即將痛宰那個女巫
when you're gonna kick that witch's ass.
我幫你
I've got you.
我擊敗不了你
I can't beat you.
那就給你想要的
So I'll give you what you want.
比利 湯米
Billy. Tommy.
媽咪 是女巫
Mommy! It's the witch!
你做了什麼？
What have you done?
-媽　-媽咪
-Mom! -Mommy!
等等 兒子
Wait! Boys!
沒事…
It's okay, it's okay. It's okay.
我是你們媽媽
I'm your mother!
不准靠近他們
Get away from them.
媽
Mom!
不
No.
還沒
Not yet.
媽咪
Mommy!
別碰我們媽媽
Get away from our mom!
-你不是我們的真媽媽　-住手
-You're not our real mom! -Hey, boys. Stop.
-拜託…　-滾出我們家
-Please. Please. -Get out of our house!
兒子 住手
Boys, stop it.
你不是我們媽媽　-出去
-You're not our mom! -Get out!
-走開　-快走
-Go away! -Go!
住手
Stop it!
拜託別傷害我們
Please don't hurt us.
求求你
Please.
我絕對不會傷害你們
I would never hurt you.
絕對不會
Never.
我絕對不會傷害任何人
I would never hurt anyone.
我不是怪物
I'm not a monster.
我是…
I'm a...
I'm...
對不起
I'm sorry.
媽
Mom!
-你還好嗎？　-嗨
-Are you okay? -Hi.
嗨 沒事
Hi. Okay.
我沒事
I'm okay.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
-媽 不要去　-媽 不要
-Mom, don't go. Don't go. -No, Mom. Don't.
-沒關係　-媽
-It's okay. -Mom.
沒關係
It's okay. It's okay.
有人會愛他們的
Know that they'll be loved.
現在呢？
What now?
離開這裡
Get out of here.
我再去找你
I'll find you.
我們該走了 快
We have to go. Now!
我打開了黑暗神書
I opened the Darkhold.
必須把它闔上
I have to close it.
沒有人會再受黑暗神書誘惑了
No one will ever be tempted by the Darkhold again.
你還好嗎？
You all right?
-結束了嗎？　-對
-Is it over? -Yeah.
阿美莉卡沒事吧？
Is America okay?
她正要過來接我們
She's on her way here to get us.
旺達呢？
Wanda?
沒有
No.
她摧毀了每個宇宙的黑暗神書
So she destroyed the Darkhold in every universe.
她做對了
She did the right thing.
沒錯
Yeah, she did.
你的宇宙是什麼樣子？
What's your universe like?
非常美
It's very beautiful.
真希望我能帶你去看
I wish I could show you.
我很想去
I'd really like that.
-但我該走了　-對
-But I have to go. -Yeah.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
太可惜了
It's too bad, though.
原本可能會有一次對撞事件
Could've been one hell of an Incursion.
我愛你
I love you.
我在每個宇宙都愛你
I love you in every universe.
我也想關心一個人或有人來關心我
It's not that I don't wanna care for someone or have someone care for me.
只是…
It's just...
我很害怕
I get scared.
是
Yeah.
是啊
面對你的恐懼
Face your fears...
奇異博士
Doctor Strange.
這怎麼比多重宇宙傳送還要難？
How is this so much harder than a Multiversal portal?
她需要放慢腳步 更有耐心
She needs to slow down and be more patient.
讓我想起另一個學生
Reminds me of another student I knew.
感覺如何？
How you feeling?
為何這麼問？
Why do you ask?
你用黑暗神書夢行到自己的屍體裡
You used the Darkhold to Dreamwalk into your own corpse.
對喔
Yeah, right, that.
沒事
Fine.
我倒是想問你一件事
But I do wanna ask you something.
你幸福嗎？
Are you happy?
這問題…
That's a...
有意思
interesting question.
原本以為拯救世界會獲得幸福
You'd think that saving the world would get you there...
並沒有
but it doesn't.
有時我忍不住會幻想其他宇宙的生活
Sometimes, I do wonder about my other lives.
但我還是很感恩在這裡
Yet I remain grateful in this one.
即使有種種苦難
Even with its tribulations.
至少我們不必獨自面對
At least we don't have to go through it alone, huh?
沒錯
No, we don't.
等一下
Wait.
你好
'Sup?
'Sup.
我創造了一些火花
Made some sparks.
很好
Great.
你的雙親會很驕傲
Your parents would be proud.
希望以後她們能看到
I hope you'll get to show 'em one day.
史蒂芬
Stephen.
我很高興落入你的宇宙
I'm glad I fell into your universe.
我也很高興 小鬼
So am I, kid.
我也很高興
So am I.
奇異博士2：失控多重宇宙
奇異博士？
Doctor Strange?
有什麼事嗎？
Can I help you?
你引發對撞事件
You caused an Incursion...
我們必須解決
and we're gonna fix it.
除非你怕了
Unless you're afraid.
一點也不怕
Not in the least.
潤色：Seethrough
翻譯：Aaron Wu
雙語合併：James、xz
（奇異博士將再回歸）
結束了
It's over！